Here's our coding solution for the share action
provider. Lets start by adding a string. The
string will be used for the label for our action. Now we're going to add a new
menu resource. This resource will be for the
detail fragment. We'll start by adding the name
space used by the Android support library for
it's widget XML. Finally, we add the actual item.
This menu item contains the string that we
just added from the strings file. It's always
shown as an action. So it appears on
the action bar. And it's actionProviderClass, is the ShareActionProvider
from the Android support library. The Android support
library allows the ShareActionProvider to be used on earlier
versions of Android then 4.0. When it was
officially added to the framework. Next, let's go to
the DetailAactivity. We're going to be looking at the
DetailFragment within the DetailActivity. So the first thing
we can do in our fragment is to add a few useful things. Let's add a log
tag, a string for the share hashtag, hashtag
sunshineApp, and we're going to take the forecast
string and make it a member variable. Next
in onCreate view, let's actually populate our member variable.
And then finally, use it to set the text.
Lets create a share intent. This intent uses ACTION_SEND.
This flag activity cleared when task reset is somewhat
important. It prevents the activity we're sharing to from
being place onto the activity stack. What will happen,
if we don't have this flag, is when you
click on the icon to return to the application
later, you may actually end up in another application.
The one that's actually handling the share intent. When
FLAG_ACTIVITY_CLEAR_WHEN_TASK_RESET is used, it'll actually return you to your
application instead. We've set the type, test/plain, to let
Android know we're going to be sharing plain text. And
then we share our forecast string plus our hashtag.
Only one more thing left to do. We have
to add the menu to the fragment. To do
this, we have to set a flag that this fragment
has an options menu at all. Otherwise, it
won't actually call the onCreate options menu member
function. Finally, here's our on creat options member
function. As you can see, we're inflating the
detailfragment menu that we created earlier. Finding the
share item, getting the ShareActionProvider, and attaching our
intent to this ShareActionProvider. You'll want to update
this whenever the data you want to share changes.
And that's it. You've now added a ShareActionProvider into Sunshine.